ilabsolutions.com 2018-12-07

# Agilent | Chemical Analysis , Life Sciences, and Diagnostics

_This Privacy Statement was last revised on May 22, 2018._

Agilent Technologies, Inc. and its subsidiaries (also referred to in this document as “ **Agilent Technologies** ”, “ **Agilent** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **our** ” and “ **us** ”) are committed to protecting and maintaining your privacy. Agilent Technologies, Inc. is established in the United States, with our registered office at 5301 Stevens Creek Boulevard, Santa Clara, CA 95051, United States and for the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (the “ **GDPR** ”), we are the data controller for all information processed in relation to the Website. The subsidiary you contract with will be the data controller of information provided for the purposes of marketing and providing the any Agilent services. This privacy statement (“ **Privacy Statement** ”) is designed to make you aware of our privacy practices, of the types of information that we collect from you and how that information will be used both when you use our website and client portal at [www.agilent.com](http://www.agilent.com/) (the “ **Website** ”) or interact with us offline in relation to providing or receiving goods and/or services. To make this notice easy to access, a link to it is available on the bottom of every Agilent web page.

If you wish to contact Agilent regarding your personal information or this Privacy Statement, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [data-protection.officer@agilent.com](mailto:data-protection.officer@agilent.com).

This Privacy Statement covers the collection, treatment and use of any personal information gathered by Agilent from customers, suppliers, vendors and other entities that Agilent does business with.

This Privacy Statement does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third-party websites, services and applications that you elect to access through our Website.

If you do not agree with this Privacy Statement in general or any part of it, you should not access the Website. Please take a moment to review our policies and practices described below.

Throughout this Privacy Statement, “personal information” refers to any information that identifies you (either alone or together with other information), such as your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, etc.

## 1\. What Information We Collect

###  1.1 Customers and Vendors

During the course of your relationship with us, we collect personal information such as your name, postal address, telephone number, fax number, e-mail address, contact and billing information, transaction history (including order, lead, demo and service/repair history) and credit card or other financial information (which shall be encrypted).

Through your in-person communications and/or online interactions with Agilent, we will ask you to provide information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products and contact preferences. We will combine the information you provide to us through different communications and contact channels, such as combining data collected online with information provided offline. In addition, personal information will be required to determine access eligibility for certain restricted parts of our Website.

Further categories of information we collect are set out in Section 2 (How we use your personal information) below.

### 1.2 All visitors to Agilent websites

While you are visiting our Website, we may collect some technical data related to your browsing session such as IP address, browser type and language, number of visits to our Website and the hyperlinks you visited.

We use such technical data in aggregate form, save as indicated in the paragraph below, without identifying you personally for Agilent’s own reporting, statistics and website enhancements, as well as for information security purposes

Login or other tracking information that may identify you through website navigation will be stored for short time periods for technical security, website improvements, customer relationship purposes and so far as you continue interacting with Agilent.

Please see Section 8 (How we use cookies) below for our use of cookies and similar technologies.

##  2\. How We Use Your Personal Information

Agilent will use the personal information that we collect from you for the general purposes set out below. As it is in our legitimate interests to be responsive to you, to ensure the proper functioning of our products and organisation and to provide you with a better service, we will use your personal information as follows.

  * We will use your contact and sign-in information such as your name, postal address, telephone number, fax number and e-mail address for the following purposes:

    * To communicate with you if you submit a query or request a quote.
    * To determine access eligibility for certain restricted parts of our Website.
    * To sign you up if you subscribe to receive our newsletter or content or if you sign up for our webinars.

  * We will also use your contact details and sign in information when you interact with our services divisions (such as the Diagnostics and Genomics Group (DGG), Agilent CrossLab Group (ACG) or Life Science and Applied Markets Group (LSAG)):

    * To provide the services to you, including providing quotes, proposals, demonstrations and generating contracts.
    * To provide customer services to you, including set-up and installation of products, processing and investigating complaints, providing professional services training and certification.
    * To conduct research and development, provide quality assurance and product validation.
    * To process our regulatory filings in association with medical devices.
    * To comply with our regulatory requirements for compliance purposes.
    * To perform services and support on our products.
    * To improve our services and products.
    * To facilitate our annual conferences.
    * To provide a mail list, to facilitate a forum to discuss our products.
    * To provide marketing communications to you with your consent, improve our brand management and conduct market research.

For further detail on our data processing in relation to our services divisions, including information about the legal bases we rely on, please see here.

  * We will use your usage information, such as your IP address, browser type, number of visits to our Website and the hyperlinks for the following purposes:

    * To respond to technical or service problems;
    * To personalise our Website and communications;
    * To ensure content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your device;
    * To monitor and analyse trends, usage and activity in connection with our Website and to improve our Website;
    * To administer the Website and for internal operations, in order to conduct troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey analysis;
    * To keep the Website safe and secure; and
    * To measure and understand the effectiveness of the content that we serve to you and others.

  * As part of the legal and regulatory obligations that we are subject to, we may also use your contact, usage and payment information to comply with such obligations and to comply with governmental and regulatory decisions.
  * We will use your personal information to better understand your needs and to provide you with a better service, including by responding to your correspondence, and providing updates on services and benefits.
  * Whenever we collect credit card numbers or other financial data, the data is only used for payment processing and the data is not retained for any other purpose.

From time to time in accordance with applicable law, we may also use your information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. To unsubscribe from promotional emails, please click [here](http://www.agilent.com/cs/agilent/en-us/globaloptout/form) or see Section 3 (Marketing Communications) below for more information.

**User Forums**

The Website may contain areas where users can transmit or post communications, for example on blogs, chat rooms, bulletin boards or user forums. You should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in such public areas.

To find out further detail as to how we process personal data as part of our business lines, _learn more_ _learn more_

**Why we collect your data**

| 

**Categories of personal data**

| 

**Legal basis for processing**

| 

**Retention period***  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Marketing communications including newsletters, webinars, and direct marketing.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

| 

Consent – we obtain opt in consent before marketing to contacts.

Legitimate interests of marketing to new and existing customers.

| 

5 years.  
  
Presales activities including provision of quotes, proposals, customer demos, producing contracts.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

| 

Legitimate interests of selling products and services to new and existing customers.

| 

6 years from expiration of customer agreement.  
  
Sale of goods and services

| 

Name, title, contact details including email address and telephone number

Financial information including bank account and credit card details

| 

Legitimate interests of selling products and services to new and existing customers

| 

10 years.  
  
Customer services including complaint investigation and compliance activities.

Provision of professional services including certification and training for clinical trials, support, training.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

| 

Legitimate interests of supporting existing customers.

| 

Service and support records are retained for 5 years post expiration of the customer agreement save for where specific Product Line retention periods apply – please refer to your Customer contract.

Records related to product installation/associated training are kept from the date of install for 15 years.

Records related to complaints and compliance activities are retained in line with our obligations for regulated devices (e.g. by the FDA) and other regulatory and legal requirements.  
  
Research and development (“ **R &D**”), quality assurance, product validation (product testing pre-sales).

External clinical studies.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

| 

Legitimate interests in testing, evaluating and improving Agilent products and services.

| 

Records relating to R&D for new products are maintained until such time as they are no longer required for R&D purposes.

Other records not relating to R&D are retained for 2 years from when they are created.  
  
Clinical trial studies and associated regulatory filings.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number

Qualifications and educational background information including, curriculum vitae information, medical licenses, registrations and any board certifications.

Financial information including a Financial Disclosure (FD) forms which lists the individual and any of their immediate family members who may have an investment in Agilent or the Pharma Partner involved in the trial.

Health data, pseudonymized patient IDs (cannot be connected back to a patient).

| 

We receive this information only to fulfill Agilent legal obligations in re: to FDA filings associated with the Clinical Trial in question; Note that these cannot be connected back to a patient.

Processing necessary for scientific purposes associated with conducting clinical trials.

| 

Clinical trials data are kept for as long as the agreement is in place with Agilent’s Pharma Partners + 2 years minimum per FDA guidance.

Records associated with US regulatory approval will be kept indefinitely in line with FDA standards. For any other Clinical Trials data, this would fall under the 2 year retention period (post agreement with a Pharma Partner).  
  
Installation and access to product platforms.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

| 

Legitimate interest to provide individual access to Agilent’s product platforms.

| 

15 years.  
  
Customer satisfaction and product feature surveys.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

IP Address.

| 

Consent obtained when requesting customer to respond to survey.

Legitimate interests of marketing to new and existing customers.

| 

6 years.  
  
To facilitate annual conferences for customers where Agilent advertises new features, updates, product road maps.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

Employment information related to where a conference attendee is currently employed.

Financial information, including transaction and credit card details used to pay for conference attendance.

| 

Legitimate interests of marketing to new and existing customers.

| 

3 years.

Financial information is destroyed as soon as the registration transaction is complete.  
  
Customer listServ (mail list) providing customers a forum to discuss the product.

| 

Name, title and contact details including email address and telephone number.

Employment information related to where a Listserv contributor is employed.

| 

Consent to participate in the mail list.

Legitimate interests of processing forum data to sell products and services to new and existing customers.

| 

User data is kept until opt out.  
  
*Individual retention periods may apply to specific product lines please refer to the terms and conditions of the product.

We note that in several of our divisions, we process personal data as a data processor when providing the services. We process such data on our client instructions and in accordance with the terms of our services agreements and customer contracts.

## 3\. Marketing Communications

To the extent permitted by applicable laws (including only with your consent where required by applicable laws), we will send you periodic marketing messages from Agilent, including newsletters, promotions and special offers. We will use your name, postal address, telephone number, fax number, social media profile and email address to send these messages to you. You are able to opt out of receiving such messages without any negative effect to your relationship with Agilent by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each marketing email. However, please note that opting out will prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or special offers. If you opt out of such marketing messages, we will continue to send you non-marketing emails, e.g. emails about our business dealings with you. We also reserve the right to contact you when we believe it necessary, including where required by law.

We will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you wish to opt out at any time of other contacts from Agilent and without any negative effect to your relationship with Agilent, and we will do everything we can to honor such requests. This choice will be offered at the bottom of our online or offline communications to you as well as on our web registration pages.

If you have any difficulty opting out, please use this unsubscribe [form](http://www.agilent.com/cs/agilent/en-us/globaloptout/form).

## 4\. Where We Store and Who We Share Your Personal Information With

The personal information that we collect from you in relation to the provision of our Website will be transferred to, and processed in the USA by Agilent Technologies, Inc. so that we can perform our contractual obligations with you.

The personal information that we collect from you in relation to the selling of our products and services will be subject to the terms of the local Agilent subsidiary you contract with. Where the GDPR applies, such personal information will be transferred to, and processed in the USA by Agilent Technologies, Inc. under the European Commission’s model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries (i.e., the standard contractual clauses) (the “ **Model Clauses** ”), pursuant to Decision 2004/915/EC and 2010/87/EU. Please contact privacy_advocate@agilent.com, if you would like to see a copy of the Model Clauses.

In addition to the above, Agilent’s global organizational structure also requires the global transfer of personal information within the Agilent group of companies. As a consequence, as it is in our legitimate interests for the efficient operation of a global company, and as permitted by applicable law, the personal information that you provide to us will be transferred across state or country borders, including to countries outside the country in which you reside (including to countries outside the EEA), to consolidate data storage, simplify information management or synchronize customer relationship activities globally. It will also be processed by staff operating outside the country in which you reside (including countries outside of the EEA) who work for us or one of our resellers, distributors, service providers or suppliers as noted below.

We share your information with selected recipients. These categories of recipients include:

  * Cloud storage providers to store the personal information you provide and for disaster recovery services;
  * Service providers that provide us with customer relationship management services;
  * Services providers that provide us with survey services;
  * Service providers that provide us with market research services;
  * Agents and suppliers that provide us with technology services;
  * Authorized service providers for field service engineering;
  * Distributors of our products and services;
  * Sales management services providers that provide us with SaaS services;
  * Services providers including that provide us with invoicing services; and
  * Our professional advisors, auditors and business partners;
  * Support providers to provide customer support services.

Where the GDPR applies and the recipient of your personal information is located outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”), such transfer will either be: (i) to a recipient certified to the US Department of Commerce's EU-US Privacy Shield; or (ii) subject to the Model Clauses. For more information about the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield [website](https://www.commerce.gov/page/eu-us-privacy-shield). If you would like to see a copy of the Model Clauses, please contact [privacy_advocate@agilent.com](mailto:privacy_advocate@agilent.com).

Agilent does not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to others except as described in this Privacy Statement.

Agilent will also disclose your personal information: (i) if we are required to do so by law; (ii) if we believe that it is necessary to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements or otherwise protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Agilent or that of our customers; (iii) in order to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or other legal obligation or government inquiry; or (iv) to any entity that acquires any part of Agilent’s current operations by way of merger, de-merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or usage of your personal information, as well as any choices you have regarding your personal information.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Statement. 

## 5\. How long We Store Your Personal Information For

We will retain your personal information in accordance with the retention periods set out in the tables above in Section 1 ( _What information we collect_ ), [here](https://www.agilent.com/en/how-we-process-personal-data).

## 6\. YOUR RIGHTS

**Where GDPR applies you have the following rights.**

**Access and Portability** : You have the right to ask us to access the personal data we hold about you and be provided with certain information about how we use your personal data and who we share it with.

Where you have provided your personal data to us with your consent, you have the right to ask us for a copy of this data in a structured, machine readable format and to ask us to share (port) this data to another data controller.

**Correction** : You also have the right to ask us to correct your personal data where it is inaccurate or incomplete.

**Right to deletion** : In certain circumstances, you have the right to ask us to delete the personal data we hold about you. Find out further information about your right to delete _here_ _here_

  * where you believe that it is no longer necessary for us to hold your personal data;
  * where we are processing your personal data on the basis of legitimate interests and you object to such processing and we cannot demonstrate an overriding legitimate ground for the processing;
  * where you have provided your personal data to us with your consent and you wish to withdraw your consent and there is no other ground under which we can process your personal data; or
  * where you believe the personal data we hold about you is being unlawfully processed by us.

**Restriction** : In certain circumstances, you have the right to ask us to restrict (stop any active) processing of your personal data. Find out further information about your ability to restrict data processing _here_ _here_

  * where you believe the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate and while we verify accuracy;
  * where we want to erase your personal data as the processing is unlawful but you want us to continue to store it;
  * where we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of our processing but you require us to retain the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
  * where you have objected to us processing your personal data based on our legitimate interests and we are considering your objection.

In addition, you can object to our processing of your personal data based on our legitimate interests and we will no longer process your personal data unless we can demonstrate an overriding legitimate ground.

To exercise any of these rights above, please click [here](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/08227516-8056-4604-9c45-2f9af0531747). In addition, you have the right to complain to any applicable data protection supervisory authority.

Please note that these rights are limited, for example, where fulfilling your request would adversely affect other individuals or company trade secrets or intellectual property, where there are overriding public interest reasons or where we are required by law to retain your personal data.

You can withdraw your consent at any time by clicking [here](https://www.agilent.com/cs/agilent/en-us/globaloptout/form).

At any time, you have the right to object to our processing of data about you in order to send you marketing, including where we build profiles for such purposes, and we will stop processing the data for that purpose.

In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how we process your personal information, please contact us in the first instance at privacy_advocate@agilent.com and we will endeavour to deal with your request as soon as possible. This is without prejudice to your right to raise a complaint with a relevant supervisory authority in the country in which you live or work, where you think we have infringed data protection laws.

## 7\. How We Keep Your Personal Information Secure

Agilent is committed to ensuring the security of your personal information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and organizational measures to safeguard and secure it. We will store personal information in locations outside our direct control (e.g. on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers) and ensure that we have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place with such providers.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share this password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information over the internet is not completely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk.

If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [privacy_advocate@agilent.com](mailto:privacy_advocate@agilent.com).

## 8\. How We Use Cookies

While you are visiting our Website, we collect technical data related to your browsing session such as IP address, browser type and language, number of visits to our Website and the hyperlinks you visited.

We use such technical data in aggregate form without identifying you personally for Agilent’s own reporting, statistics and website enhancements, as well as for information security purposes.

For further details about the data we collect through cookies, their purpose and your choices in relation to cookies, please _see here_ _see here_

**Types of Data Collected Through Cookies and Purposes of Cookies’ Use**

Agilent uses technologies, such as web-tracking tools designed for website session analysis and profiling of the users of our Website. Such technologies enable us to optimize our Website content and tailor it and other communications to you.

A cookie is text file containing small amounts of information stored on your computer’s hard drive when you visit a webpage. You can find more information about cookies and how to manage them at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

The main purpose of a cookie is to allow a web server to identify a user and serve up customized web pages and/or login information to the user's web browser when revisiting a web page. These cookies help you avoid entering identification details each time you visit our Website or repeatedly type the same information you are looking for on our Website (search terms, key words, names of products, etc.).

Cookies also help us to promptly display the information you need and other information which we consider are of interest to you.

We will use session cookies (which are deleted after each session) and stored cookies (which remain on your hardware after your session has ended). Cookies will be set by a third party operating on our behalf (e.g. to help us analyze web traffic or to improve your web navigation experience).

**Cookie. Clear Gif. Tag and Script Usage and Your Choices About Tracking Technologies**

We use the following types of cookies on our Website to help us analyze web traffic, to improve your web experience and to better target our marketing of products and services:

  * Strictly necessary cookies, which are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features.
  * Performance cookies, which collect information about how you use the website, for instance which pages you visit most often.
  * Functionality cookies, which allow the website to remember choices you make (e.g. remembering your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features.
  * Advertising cookies, which are used to deliver advertisements more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign.

To facilitate the analysis of web traffic, an ID is assigned to help us uniquely identify you each time you return to our Website.

By gathering and remembering information about your website preferences through cookies we can provide a better web and marketing experience. Specifically, cookies enable us to:

  * Tailor our Website’s operation to your needs, likes and dislikes.
  * Provide an automated log-in process as a convenience for previously registered customers, ensuring that you will be identified accurately and linked with your registration data.
  * Ensure you are not surveyed multiple times during your visit(s) to an Agilent website.
  * Provide a better web experience by letting us monitor what is working and what is not.

We also partner with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our Website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. Our ad network partners also use cookies for re-targeting, therefore you may see an advertisement for our services on a third party site you visit after visiting our site. If you do not want your information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you can opt out by clicking [_Here_](http://preferences.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [_here_](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

As a user you have the ability to accept or decline the use of cookies. Where required by law, Agilent indicates its use of cookies through a prominent banner on our Website. Cookies can be removed explicitly using functionality built into most web browsers and you can refuse to accept cookies by activating this setting on your browser. You can also set up your web browser to notify you of cookie placement requests, to ask for permission to accept them, or to decline cookies completely. For information on how to adjust your browser regarding cookies, please visit:

Microsoft Internet Explorer: <http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm>  
Firefox: <https://support.mozilla.org/t5/Protect-your-privacy/Enable-and-disable-cookies-that-websites-use-to-track-your/ta-p/2784>  
Chrome: <http://www.google.com/support/chrome/?hl=en>  
Safari: <http://www.apple.com/support/safari/>  
Opera: <http://www.opera.com/browser/tutorials/security/>

If you choose to decline cookies, parts of the Website will be unavailable to you.

**Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information will include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We use this information to improve services we offer you, analytics and site functionality. We do not use this data for any other purpose.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs), Tags, and Scripts**

Technologies such as: cookies (as detailed above), clear gifs, tags and scripts are used by us and our analytics companies Google Analytics and Eloqua. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We will receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We also will use Clear Gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. For this reason, Clear Gifs will be tied to your personal information.

**Website Tracking**

We use Google Analytics and Eloqua, which are web analytics tools, to help us understand how users engage with our Website. Like many services, Google Analytics and Eloqua track your movement through our site (i.e. the pages you have seen and the links you have clicked on) and help us measure how you interact with the content that we provide. This information is used to compile reports and to help us improve our Website. The reports disclose website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of accepting cookies but this affect your personalised experience of Agilent.com.

For further details about the data we collect through cookies, their purpose and your choices in relation to cookies, please see [[here](https://preferences.truste.com/)].

## 9\. Additional Information

**Links to Third-Party Websites**

Links to third-party websites are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the Agilent website. Agilent has not reviewed, does not control and is not responsible for these websites, their content or their privacy statement. Thus, we do not endorse or make any representations about them, any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results of using them. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to Agilent’s website, you do so entirely at your own risk.

**Jobs@Agilent**

When you choose to post a resume to our Website and apply to become part of the Agilent team, please note that you will be taken to a third-party URL ([jobs.agilent.com](http://jobs.agilent.com/)) and these pages will be branded as Agilent. The information you provide via the URL will be used solely for the purposes for which it is provided (including the processing of your application) and will be retained for such period as is necessary to comply with Agilent’s legal and administrative requirements. The information collected and used while on these hosted pages is subject to the following sections of this Privacy Statement to the extent applicable to resumes: How We use Cookies; Who we share your personal information with; How long we store your personal information for; and How we keep your personal information secure.

For candidates applying for jobs in Europe, please refer to our [Candidate Privacy Notice](http://careers.agilent.com/media/21286/agilent-gdpr-candidate-portal-privacy-policy.pdf) which provides information about how Agilent uses your personal information.

**Email a Page**

If you choose to use our Email a Page service, your name, comments and the email addresses you provide will not be used for any other purpose than to complete this page-forwarding transaction.

**Changes to the Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement is effective as of the date stated at the start of this Privacy Statement. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the revised policy on our Website and updating the date the statement was last revised at the start of this Privacy Statement, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by email or by means of a prominent notice on our home page. Unless we ask for your explicit agreement to certain terms of our policy, we consider that your continuous use of our Website means that you accept the terms of this Privacy Statement.

**Contact Information**

Please send/contact us with questions or comments about our privacy practices at:

Data Protection Officer at [data-protection.officer@agilent.com](mailto:data-protection.officer@agilent.com)

Agilent Technologies, Inc.  
5301 Stevens Creek Blvd.  
Santa Clara, CA 95051  
USA

Phone: (408) 553 -4417
